Hello English learners, welcome to another great lesson with EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
So, Erika, how are you today?
那么，Erika，你今天怎么样？
I'm doing pretty well.
我挺好的。
And I think we've got a good lesson today, a really helpful lesson.
而且我觉得我们今天有一堂好课，一堂非常有用的课。
What are we talking about today?
我们今天要讲什么？
We have an elementary lesson about making an appointment.
我们有一节关于预约的初级课程。
Alright, making an appointment.
好的，预约。
Yeah, that's really helpful.
是啊，这真的很有用。
I guess you have to make appointments for the doctor or...
我想你得预约看医生或者……
At work maybe.
也许在工作中。
At work, personal.
工作中，个人事务。
Or with your friends, yeah.
或者和朋友，是的。
So, this is language that you can use every day to make appointments.
所以，这是你每天都可以用来预约的语言。
Great.
太好了。
Well, so, why don't we take a look at our vocabulary preview.
那么，我们为什么不先看一下词汇预览呢。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
We only have one word today which you need to know to understand this dialogue.
今天只有一个词你需要知道才能理解这段对话。
And it is financial advisor.
那就是财务顾问。
Financial advisor.
财务顾问。
So, what is a financial advisor?
那么，什么是财务顾问？
A financial advisor is a person who gives suggestions or recommendations about investing
财务顾问是就投资提供建议或推荐的人。
money.
钱。
Someone who wants you to put money in the stock market.
想让你把钱投进股市的人。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
I guess we're ready now to listen to our dialogue for the first time.
我想我们现在可以第一次听对话了。
And as always, it's going to be at a normal speed, but you don't have to worry about it
和往常一样，它会以正常语速播放，但你不用担心，
because...
因为……
We'll come back and teach you all the important words.
我们会回来教你所有重要的词汇。
Hello?
喂？
Fairbrook Consulting.
Fairbrook咨询公司。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes, this is Julianne Horton.
是的，我是Julianne Horton。
And I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. McNeely.
我打电话来是想和McNeely女士预约。
Certainly.
当然可以。
What day were you thinking of?
您想约哪一天？
How's Thursday?
星期四怎么样？
Does she have any time available then?
她那时有空吗？
Um, let me double check.
嗯，让我再确认一下。
Unfortunately, she's booked solid on Thursday.
不幸的是，她周四的日程全满了。
How does next Monday work for you?
下周一您方便吗？
Actually, I've got something scheduled on Monday.
实际上，我周一已经有安排了。
Can't you do Tuesday?
周二不行吗？
Sure, Tuesday's perfect.
当然，周二很合适。
May I ask where you're calling from?
请问您是从哪里打来的？
Sure.
好的。
Merton Financial Advisors.
默顿财务顾问公司。
Oh.
哦。
Actually, Tuesday's no good.
实际上，周二也不行。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Well, I guess Ms. McNeely does not want to speak to any financial advisors.
嗯，我想麦克尼利女士不想和任何财务顾问通话。
Yeah, I guess she doesn't really want to invest in the stock market.
是啊，我猜她并不想投资股市。
Or maybe she just gets too many phone calls from them.
或者她只是接到太多这种电话了。
Yeah.
是啊。
If you have money, I guess you'll get phone calls from people like that.
如果你有钱，我想你就会接到这种电话。
I guess we don't have that problem, hey?
我想我们没有这个问题，对吧？
No, we don't.
对，我们没有。
Okay, let's start with our language takeaway for today.
好的，我们开始今天的语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So four words today.
今天有四个词。
The first one is available.
第一个是 available。
Available.
Available。
Available, meaning that you are not busy.
Available，意思是你没有在忙。
That you're free.
你有空。
You're free.
You're not busy.
你不忙。
Exactly.
没错。
Let's move to our next word.
我们来看下一个词。
Double check.
Double check。
I think we've got some examples of this phrase.
我想我们有一些这个短语的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Do you have the tickets?
你有票吗？
I think so, but let me just double check.
我想有，但让我再确认一下。
Example two.
例子二。
I thought I sent that email already, but let me double check.
我以为我已经发了那封邮件，但还是让我再确认一下。
Okay, so double check basically means to check something twice.
好的，所以 double check 基本上就是检查两次的意思。
Exactly.
没错。
To check it again.
再检查一遍。
Check it again.
Okay.
好的。
Our third word for language takeaway today is scheduled.
今天语言要点的第三个词是 scheduled。
Scheduled.
Scheduled。
S-C-H-E-D-U-L-D.
S-C-H-E-D-U-L-D。
Scheduled.
Scheduled。
So, when you have something scheduled, it means that you have something planned, right?
所以，当你有 scheduled 的事情，意思就是你有计划好的事情，对吧？
Yeah, or booked at that time.
是的，或者那个时间已经预订了。
Booked at that time.
那个时间已经预订了。
Yeah.
是的。
We've got a lunch scheduled this afternoon, don't we?
我们今天下午安排了一顿午餐，对吧？
Yes, we do.
是的，没错。
All right.
好的。
A great lunch.
一顿很棒的午餐。
Looking forward to it.
很期待。
And our last word for today is booked solid.
今天最后一个词是 booked solid。
Booked solid.
Booked solid。
B-O-O-K-E-D.
B-O-O-K-E-D。
Booked solid.
Booked solid。
So, we have some great words for today.
所以，我们今天有一些很棒的词。
We have a great word for today.
我们今天有一个很棒的词。
We have a great phrase for today, which is booked solid.
我们今天有一个很棒的短语，就是 booked solid。
So, we have some great examples on how you can use this great phrase, booked solid, and
所以，我们有一些很好的例子，展示如何使用这个很棒的短语 booked solid，并且
you can understand what it means.
你可以理解它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
I can't get a hotel room.
我订不到酒店房间。
They're booked solid until after the New Year.
他们一直到新年之后都预订满了。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm sorry, there are no seats available on this flight.
抱歉，这趟航班没有空位了。
I'm booked solid over the Christmas holidays.
我在圣诞假期期间日程排得满满的。
Example three.
例子三。
Sorry, I can't meet with you today.
抱歉，我今天不能见你。
I'm booked solid.
我日程排满了。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So, booked solid basically is?
那么，booked solid 基本上就是？
You have no free time, no available time.
你没有空闲时间，没有可用的时间。
Right.
对。
So, you've got appointments scheduled all day.
所以，你整天都有预约安排。
All day, great.
一整天，很好。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
So, with this in mind, now we can listen to our dialogue a second time.
那么，记住这一点，我们现在可以再听一遍对话。
This time, it's going to be slow, so we can understand a little bit better.
这次会慢速播放，这样我们能更好地理解。
Hello, Fairbrook Consulting.
你好，Fairbrook 咨询公司。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes, this is Julianne Horton, and I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. McNeely.
是的，我是 Julianne Horton，我打电话来是想和 McNeely 女士预约见面。
Certainly.
当然可以。
What date were you thinking of?
您想约哪一天？
How's Thursday?
周四怎么样？
Does she have any time available then?
她那时有空吗？
Um, let me double check.
嗯，让我再确认一下。
No, unfortunately, she's booked solid on Thursday.
不，很遗憾，她周四的日程排满了。
How does next Monday work for you?
下周一您方便吗？
Actually, I've got something scheduled on Monday.
实际上，我周一已经有安排了。
Can she do Tuesday?
她能周二见吗？
Sure, Tuesday's perfect.
当然，周二很合适。
May I ask where you're calling from?
请问您是从哪里打来的？
Sure, Merton Financial Advisors.
我是 Merton 金融顾问公司的。
Oh.
哦。
Actually, Tuesday's no good.
实际上，周二不行。
Sorry about that.
抱歉。
Okay, so now it's a little bit more clear, and with this, we can start with putting it together.
好的，现在更清楚了一些，有了这个，我们可以开始把它们整合起来。
Putting it together.
整合起来。
There's some great examples in this dialogue of phrases you can use when you need to schedule an appointment, and we're going to look at those today.
这段对话中有一些很好的例子，展示了在需要预约时可以用到的短语，我们今天就来学习这些。
In the dialogue, we heard Julianne ask about making an appointment, and she said this.
在对话中，我们听到 Julianne 询问预约的事，她说了这样一句话。
I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. McNeely.
我打电话来是想和 McNeely 女士预约见面。
So this is a great way to schedule an appointment, to ask for some time from somebody else.
所以这是预约、向别人要时间的一个好方法。
Yeah, and we have some more examples of this phrase.
是的，我们还有更多这个短语的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Please book an appointment for next week.
请预约下周的时间。
Example two.
例子二。
Please schedule an appointment for next week.
请安排下周的预约。
Great, so after that, when you're scheduling an appointment, you need to suggest a day when maybe that person has time.
很好，那么在那之后，当你安排预约时，你需要建议一个对方可能有空的日子。
Yes, let's listen to what they said in the dialogue.
是的，我们来听听他们在对话中说了什么。
How's Thursday? Does she have any time available then?
周四怎么样？她那时有空吗？
You say, well, how's Thursday or how's Tuesday?
你可以说，嗯，周四或周二怎么样？
And maybe that person doesn't have time that day, so they'll say something like this.
也许对方那天没空，所以他们可能会这样说。
Can't you do Tuesday?
你不能安排在周二吗？
Okay, Erica, so if I want to have a meeting with you, I would say, how's Monday sound or how's Monday?
好的，Erica，如果我想和你开会，我会说，周一听起来怎么样？或者周一如何？
Monday's no good. I'm busy all day.
周一不行。我一整天都很忙。
How's Tuesday?
周二怎么样？
Sorry, Tuesday's no good either.
抱歉，周二也不行。
What about Wednesday?
周三呢？
Okay, Wednesday works.
好的，周三可以。
All right, great.
好的，很好。
Wednesday's perfect.
周三完美。
Okay, great, so we have a meeting on Wednesday.
好的，太好了，那我们周三开会。
Okay, yeah, those are some great phrases, hey, for scheduling an appointment.
好的，是的，这些是安排预约时很好用的短语。
Yeah, they're really good.
是的，它们真的很好。
Okay, so now we can listen to our dialogue a third time and we're ready to understand everything that we've just talked about.
好的，现在我们可以第三次听对话了，我们已经准备好理解刚才讨论的所有内容。
Hello, Fairbrook Consulting. How may I help you?
你好，Fairbrook咨询公司。有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, this is Julianne Horton, and I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. McNeely.
是的，我是Julianne Horton，我打电话来是想和McNeely女士预约。
Certainly. What day were you thinking of?
当然。您想约哪一天？
How's Thursday? Does she have any time available then?
周四怎么样？她那时有空吗？
Um, let me double check.
嗯，让我再确认一下。
Unfortunately, she's booked solid on Thursday. How does next Monday work for you?
不幸的是，周四她已经排满了。下周一您方便吗？
Actually, I've got something scheduled on Monday. Can't you do Tuesday?
实际上，周一我已经有安排了。你不能安排在周二吗？
Sure, Tuesday's perfect. May I ask where you're calling from?
当然，周二很好。请问您是从哪里打来的？
Sure, Merton Financial Advisors.
Merton金融顾问公司。
Oh, actually, Tuesday's no good. Sorry about that.
哦，实际上，周二不行。抱歉。
The language in this dialogue is really useful, isn't it, Marco?
这个对话中的语言真的很有用，对吧，Marco？
Yeah, it's from an everyday situation. You always have to make appointments at some point.
是的，它来自日常场景。你总得在某个时候预约。
Yes, and like we said earlier, it's language you can use when you need to talk about work with your boss, maybe.
是的，就像我们之前说的，当你需要和老板谈工作的时候，也许可以用这些语言。
Right.
对。
Or when you need to do daily things, like go to the doctor.
或者当你需要做日常事务，比如去看医生的时候。
Or even when you're planning something with your friends.
甚至当你和朋友计划事情的时候。
Right.
对。
Yeah, you can use this in all those situations.
是的，你可以在所有这些情况下使用这些表达。
In all situations.
在所有情况下。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Great. Well, we're out of time now, but I hope you enjoyed our lesson and found it useful.
太好了。好了，我们时间到了，但我希望你喜欢我们的课程并觉得它有用。
And if you have any questions or comments, please go to our website at EnglishPod.com, where we'll be there to answer everything.
如果你有任何问题或评论，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里回答一切。
Yes, we will. So, thanks for listening, guys. And until next time, goodbye.
是的，我们会。所以，感谢收听，各位。下次再见，拜拜。
Goodbye.
再见。